Huiyao (Karen) Dong

214.603.1059 | huiyao2014@gmail.com | www.huiyaodong.com | github.com/KarenDong

SUMMARY

Fast learner, hard worker and team player who is proficient in multiple scripting languages and databases.

3 years working experience with relational database development and maintenance, and data analysis. MCSA certified.

Web development experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django framework, .Net framework, and AWS deployment.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst II

Jan. 2017 – Present

- Develop the Salesforce system, including database structure design, data migration and integration development, dashboard design
- Integrate customers and marketing multiple data sources from MIS and ERP with database tools such as MS Access and SQL Server to generate insights
- Generate scheduled monthly reports for business performance, expenses, and research of market trends and prices
- Develop analytics dashboard and automated reports with business intelligence tool like Power BI and Tableau
- Utilize VBA and Power Pivot to develop finance model and reports for performance appraisal
- Conduct statistics analysis based on raw sales data to predict trends and forecast future performance and costs

Database Analyst

Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Texas

Aug. 2016 – Dec. 2016

- Developed and maintained stored functions and procedures in Oracle
- Processed, organized, coordinated data and generated reports for commissions' analysis and adjustments
- Established Access Reporting Database System and worked with Visual Basic codes for certain projects
- Designed SQL database, developed ETL packages with SSIS for automatic data transformation in from Callidus Database and Access Database

Database Analyst Internship

Aberg Center for Literacy

Jan. 2016 - July 2016

- Built relational database and Maintained database models stored in SalesForce and MySQL
- Analyzed survey data with descriptive statistics and inferential statistics with Excel, SQL and SQQL
- Generated reports statistical graphs using VBA, Pivot table and SalesForce reporting tools
- Designed website testing and web analysis procedure

MIS Lab Assistant

The University of Texas at Dallas

Jan. 2015 – Dec. 2015

- Built Excel online course for UT Dallas students for self-study and to prepare for Excel certification exam
- Guided students weekly for their project related to Excel, Access and SQL server
- Provided information on Excel certification to students and helped them with exam preparation
- Organized Excel workshops with student organizations and instructed Excel skills

Accounting Analyst Internship

Qinhuangdao Qiushi Certified Public Accountants Co., Ltd.(China)

Sep. 2012 – Jan. 2013

- Audited and analyzed data of bank accounts and investments with MS Access for 18-20 clients monthly
- Assisted team with tax consultant and reporting by analyzing cost and taxes

Cost Analyst Internship

Sinolion Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (China)

July 2010 – Aug. 2010

- Created and maintained documentation for real estate projects to support further quality assurance research
- Analyzed data for investment evaluation using advanced Excel functions like VBA and pivot tables
- Generated cost reports monthly and on an as-needed basis with SAP, Financial Accounting module

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo Coding Camp

May 2017 - Oct. 2017

Accelerated coding boot camp graduate focused on 3 full stacks (Web Development, Python, and ASP.net)

The University of Texas at Dallas

Aug. 2014 - Aug. 2016

M.S., Information Technology Management

Huiyao (Karen) Dong

214.603.1059 | huiyao2014@gmail.com | www. huiyaodong.com | github.com/KarenDong

Yanshan University (China)

B.S., Accounting

Sep. 2009 - July 2013

CERTIFICATION

- MCSA Microsoft Certified System Administrator: SQL Server (Certification#: G136-5495)
- MTA Microsoft Technology Associate: Database Fundamentals (Certification number: F730-3159)
- UT Dallas SAS Institute Certificate in Business Intelligence and Data Mining
- Google Analytics Individual Qualification

TECHNICAL SKILL

Programming: SQL, JAVA, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Python, C#, .Net, SAS programming

Software: SQL Server 2012/2014, Toad for Oracle, MySQL, SAP, MS Access, MS Excel, SAS, Tableau, Sublime,

Visio Studio, Crystal Reports, MS Visio, MyEclipse, SalesForce, Photoshop, InDesign

Database: SQL Server 2012/2014, Toad for Oracle, MySQL, MS Access

PROJECTS

Web development - Portfolio Site

- Designed the layout and architecture of my portfolio website to develop my personal brand
- Developed my portfolio using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery

Web development - "Tree hollow"

- Designed a simplified website that allow users to register, add, edit and delete personal posts.
- Designed the database structure with MySQL and SQLite
- Developed the website using Django framework, and Deployed the website with AWS platform

Web development - "Taste N Color"

- Created and designed my personal blog to showcase my photo works
- Developed the website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery

Customer Analytics and Real-life Data Analysis with SAS Programming

Apr. 2016 – May 2016

- Built Poisson model and Beta model using base SAS
- Performed Customer Analytics such as customer retention, count models and choice models

Web Application Design (associated with Petro China Co Ltd.)

Dec. 2015 - Jan. 2016

- Designed Java based app. to analyze system reliability of pump wells of oil extractor and predict inspection cycle
- Designed database structure with MySQL Model, loaded data using ETL tools in MySQL
- Developed the web-based interface using HTML, CSS and jQuery

Business Intelligence Project for emergency department(ED)

Aug. 2015 – Dec. 2015

- Conducted data analysis for cost savings and death rate based on data from U.S. emergency departments in 2012
- · Predicted the key elements affecting the cost trend of emergency departments and death rate of patients

Java-based Software Design

Jan. 2015 – May 2015

- Designed a Java-based Optimized Shopper Application, which contains: Optimized Map system, Queue Status system, Density count system.
- Created blueprint for the system by Designed the class diagram and user case diagram
- · Analyzed database, functions covered and system working process using sequence diagram
- Designed software structure, testing methods, etc.

Database management system

Jan. 2015 – May 2015

- Designed a database system for chained retail stores using SQL Server 2012, based for real world business need
- Drew the blueprint using MS Visio 2013, developing ERD and Relational Model
- Created the interface that give different roles different admin rights with Visual Studio